synovate.com 2005-04-05

# Synovate: Research reinvented

## Disclaimer, Privacy Policy and Standard Terms of Business

**DISCLAIMER**

Whilst Synovate has taken reasonable steps to ensure that the information on this site is accurate when first made available, the information may be superseded by events or cease to be accurate subsequently. No obligation to update the information is accepted and Synovate accepts no liability for the accuracy or completeness or use of the information contained on this site. The information should not be construed as the giving of advice or the making of a recommendation and should not be relied on as a basis for any decision or action.

Actual results and developments may be materially different from any forecast, opinion or expectation expressed on this site and the past performance of the price of securities must not be relied upon as a guide to their future performance.

Nothing on this site constitutes an invitation or offer to invest or deal in the securities of Synovate's parent company Aegis Group plc or any other entity. None of the information on this site shall form the basis of any contract with Synovate or Aegis Group plc.

Sites or pages which are linked to this site are for information only; they have not been reviewed by Synovate. Synovate has no responsibility for the content of sites or pages linked or linking to this site and accepts no responsibility or liability for any losses or penalties whatsoever that might be incurred as a result of linking to any location on any linked sites or pages.

Links to other sites do not imply that Synovate or this site sponsors, endorses or is associated with, or is legally authorised to use any trade mark, trade name, logo or  
copyright symbol displayed in or accessible through the links, or that any linked site or page is authorised to use any trade mark, trade name, logo or copyright symbol of Synovate or any of its subsidiaries.

Unless otherwise stated all contents of this web site are © 2002-2004 Synovate.

**SYNOVATE PRIVACY POLICY**

Synovate believes in protecting your privacy. We will not collect any personal information from you via this web site that you do not volunteer. We do not sell, share, or rent personal information to third parties without your consent, except in certain specific cases described below. 

If you choose to register or submit personally identifiable information to us, you agree to the use of such information in accordance with this privacy policy. 

**Types of Information We Collect**

As a general visitor to this web site, Synovate does not collect any personally identifiable information about you. However, we automatically record information sent by your browser in our server logs, including your IP address, the pages you visit, and other non-personally identifiable information, which we use to analyze our web traffic and administer our servers. 

As a visitor to or member of our on-line consumer opinion panel, you may be asked to provide your name, street address, state, zip code, telephone number and/or e-mail address. Additional terms and conditions regarding your privacy as a visitor to or member of our on-line consumer opinion panel are posted on the sections of the website applicable to those activities. 

**Cookies**

On certain parts of the site, we may use cookies to enable additional functionality. If you reject cookies, you may still use the site; however, you may not be able to access all areas or features. 

**Job Applications**

If you submit a job application to Synovate, we may use the personal information that you supply, such as your email address and phone number, to contact you about possible job openings. We may also contact previous employers and references. 

**Subscription Registration**

If you register for a subscription such as Change Agent or In:Fact, we will use the registration information that you submit to process your request. We will keep this information in a database. In addition, we may contact you about future publications and Synovate services that may be of interest to you. You will always have an opportunity to opt out of receiving such communications. 

**Other Contact**

If you send email to us, we will use your email address or other contact information in order to respond to your inquiry. If you request information about our products or services, we may follow up with you in the future with additional information that we think may be of interest to you. You will always have an opportunity to opt out of receiving such communications. 

**Parties to Whom We Disclose Information**

Synovate does not disclose your personal information to anyone without your consent except in the following situations: 

  1. To comply with a validly issued and enforceable subpoena or summons, a court order, or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority.
  2. To investigate network abuse or a violation of our Terms of Use or other published guidelines.
  3. As a part of any actual or threatened legal proceedings or alternative dispute resolution proceedings either initiated by or against us.
  4. If you engage in (or are reasonably suspected of engaging in) any illegal activities.
  5. To provide information to affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties who perform services or functions for us in conjunction with any requests or inquiries made by you.

We also reserve the right to report any suspected illegal activity to law enforcement for investigation or prosecution. 

**Third Party Sites**

The site may contain links to other web sites which may or may not be owned or operated by us. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any of those web sites, including their use of any information that is collected when visitors to our site click through links to those sites or link to the site through those other sites. This Privacy Policy only addresses our use and disclosure of any information we collect from you. To the extent you disclose personal information on other web sites, even those to which you have linked through the site, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of that information to third parties. We do not control the privacy practices of those sites and therefore strongly encourages users to familiarize themselves with the privacy practices and customs of any web site controlled by a third party before disclosing any personal information on that site. 

**Changes to this Policy**

From time to time, we may revise this Privacy Policy. Please check the policy periodically for changes. 

If you have questions or concerns about this policy, if you want to correct or change any information previously provided to us, or if you have provided us with personally-identifiable information and would like that information deleted, please e-mail us at [privacy@synovate.com](mailto:privacy@synovate.com). 

**STANDARD TERMS OF BUSINESS**

Please click one of the following links to read our standard terms of business.

English.PDF)

French.PDF)

Portuguese.PDF)

Spanish.PDF)
